Eric Givens

20 Washington Street #12 **Profile** Methuen, MA 01844

eric.givens@gordon.edu

Ten year's experience supporting Macintosh and Windows hardware and software, with direct interaction with the end-user. Extensive experience with Macintosh OSX, OSX Server, and Macintosh-specific software. Experience developing database-backed web applications with open source tools.

Relevant Experience

Provided advanced support for all hardware and software requests for a campus of 500+ faculty and staff and 1600+ students, including all campus-supported software packages and all Windows and Macintosh operating systems.

Acted as primary, level 2 support on all mac-related issues, including:

- Managing student technical staff in areas relating to Mac hardware/software troubleshooting and repair for all faculty, staff and students.
- Training student technical staff and full-time staff in all areas of Mac usage and troubleshooting
- Determining standards and recommended hardware for all Mac purchases campus-wide
- Managing all public Mac maintenance & cloning, including labs, kiosks and loaner laptops
- Producing documentation and training materials for support staff and end-users, including paper and web-based documentation and organizing seminars.

Developed, deployed and maintained database-backed web applications for internal use using open source tools such as Ruby on Rails, MySQL, JQuery, etc.

Implemented, developed and maintained public-facing distribution of audio/visual content through Gordon's iTunes U site, including creation and posting of content and acquiring skills to better integrate campus technologies with iTunes U (e.g. iTunes U Web Services, Podcast Producer, etc.). Proactively coordinated with other departments on-campus for the creation of new content appropriate for iTunes U/podcasting.

Directed multi-camera video shoots for special events such as commencement exercises and produced fully edited versions of events for distribution on DVD, podcast, YouTube, etc.

Technical Proficiencies

Hand coding standards-compliant HTML and CSS, following a philosophy of 'progressive enhancement'.

Proficient in the Ruby programming language; Ruby on Rails for web application development; git (and GitHub) and for software version control; Capistrano for automated web site deployment; Apache and Nginx for web server administration; MySQL for relational databases; bash, Applescript and rake for scripting.

Software Proficiencies: All version of Macintosh OSX and Macintosh OSX Server, Apple Remote Desktop, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe ImageReady, Flash, Ubuntu 7.10

Extensive experience with Final Cut Pro, Final Cut Express, DVD Studio Pro, Motion, Soundtrack, LiveType

Work History

Assistant Director of Technology Support, Gordon College; Wenham, MA - 2003-present User Services Specialist, Gordon College; Wenham, MA - 2000-2003 Development Services Assistant, Gordon College; Wenham, MA - 1997-2000

Education

Gordon College, Wenham, MA — B.A. English, 1996